[Music]
Hello friends, I Manoj Jaiswal
heartily welcome you to this video. Today
in this video we are going to talk about
ICICI Product's Gold Plan.
Yes, it is an income plan through which you
can generate a new income for yourself, meaning you can
also create a second source of income. There are
three options in this plan.
We will understand all three options in complete detail. We will also
understand
who can take this plan, what are the basic details,
what are the eligibility criteria. We will also
understand this plan
with an example. To understand these complete things, I will
take you to my computer screen. But
before that, I
would request you that if you have come to this channel for the
first time or you have
not yet pressed the red button given below, then do
not forget to subscribe to the channel.
Definitely press the red button given below. So let's go to
your computer screen and understand
what is ICICI Potential's Gold
Plan. So now you have come to my computer
screen where I  The
presentation
of ICC Prudential's Gold Plan is open. First of all, let us
understand the features of this plan. So,
see what are the features in the features. Your
policy term will be 99 years in this plan.
99 years means you will subtract the age of your policy order
from 99 years.
After that, in whatever term is left, you will get the
complete life insurance coverage of the policy.
Secondly,
you get income till the age of 99 years with the
option whether you want immediate income, deferred income,
means you want it after some time. The
income you get as per your requirement is
guaranteed income which is
linked to the bonus declaration. Thirdly, there is an
option in this that if you want,
your future premium, if your income has
started and you want your
future premium to be
rounded off or covered by your pension or the income that is going to come, then
you can get that adjusted as well. The
third feature which has been
kept the best in this is the guaranteed booster plan.
What is there in this?  In Guaranteed Booster,
you will get a booster every fifth year.
Whatever is your annual money, you will get it. We will
understand it in detail later. If we talk about further tax
benefits, then the
tax which is applicable on this will be levied on you.
If you fall under the category of income
tax, then you will have to pay the charges.
In the basic details, the full name of this plan
is ICICI Product Gold Plan.
Talking about the plan type, it is a non-linked non-
participating individual savings life
insurance plan. The entry age is
minimum zero years, which means you can take the plan for a child
and the maximum has been kept at 60 years. The
maturity age is minimum 25 years and the maximum has been
kept at 99 years. The
plan variants in this are on the
left side. Look at the right side, there is premium
payment term, so there are different variants
like the first variant is Immediate Income.
In this, you get the option of premium payment term,
it is 5 years, 6
years and from 7 years to 12 years. The third option is the
second option.  Immediate Income with
Booster: The premium payment
option available in this is 6 years, 7 years and from 8 years
to 12 years and there is Deferred Income. The
option you get in this is 7 years, 8 years
and from 9 years to 12 years. Now
we have discussed the premium payment term, but if we
talk about the policy term, then the
policy term, as I told you earlier, is
99 years less. Whatever will be the age of the policy holder,
that policy term will be counted.
Further premium payment mode: Three
options are available in this, yearly, half yearly and
monthly quarterly. The option of quarterly is not available to you in this.
Now first of all let's talk about that
one, which is the first option,
we have that option of Immediate Income.
What happens in it, the policy starts
from the same year as you started the policy.
After that,
you will start getting your income. If you
want, you can take it on month mode or year mode.
Yes, but in this case, you have to keep in mind
that as long as your policy remains in force, it will remain in
force.  You will keep getting money till the
regular income which will follow this way You will
get guaranteed income along with
cash bonus which will be linked with the income along with the
bonus So your guaranteed
income is done CB Your cash bonus which depends on the
totality is
declared as per the percentage and not as per the
amount
How will the guaranteed income that you will get in this plan be multiplied The
guaranteed income will be
multiplied by the analyzed premium according to that
You will keep getting income term through out the policy term The
maturity
benefit that you will get in this plan is
sum saved on maturity means like the
maturity term comes to 99 years at that time the
sum stored on maturity which will be equal to the
sum total which is analyzed premium paid
plus the balance which is
lying inside your savings wallet Along with
whatever terminal bonus has been declared, this will be
your maturity benefit Now
comes the second variant  Immediate Income with Booster
Benefit What is inside it is that you will start getting income every
fifth year like in the first option,
but every fifth year as soon as five years are
completed, whatever income you were getting yearly,
you will be
given that as a booster immediately extra. In this,
you will be given it every five years
in a lot of five years. Secondly, the
guaranteed sum in this is GI, along with that you will get
GB guaranteed booster. Thirdly,
you are not getting GB in that plan.
In the first one, you are getting GB in the second one
along with GST bonus. If this
is declared, then yes, till when will you keep getting this money?
Till the
maturity of your policy does not come or the
death of the policy holder does not happen or the policy is
not surrendered or the policy has lapsed.
So, except in these cases,
you start getting this money.
After this, let us talk about
what you will get on maturity. End of policy term: So, in that case, the
time stored is maturity
which is equal to  The total premium that you have
paid will remain during the policy term
plus you will get whatever
money is left in your account wallet
along with any terminal bonus if declared then you will
get that. Now the last variant
is deferred income, what are the options in it,
like the first option you
get money, you get regular income but
not immediate, you have chosen this, if you
want money after two years, three years, four years then
three, four years, five years, whatever term you
decide, after that you will
start getting income, in this also the
maturity amount that you will get will be sum stored and at
maturity that is equal to sum stored,
whatever premium
you are paying plus the money in savings wallet plus
terminal bonus declared, you get this money in
this plan, now let's talk about
death benefit, in death benefit you get sum
on death plus balance in
savings wallet which is your wallet
which is left in it plus interim survival benefit
if any is linked then you will get that plus
terminal bonus if  If it has been declared then you will
get it along with it. The
best thing in this is
what will be the sum sum on death, what will you get, the
sum sum is
mentioned at the top, the sum sum will be either
seven times the analysed premium that you are paying,
if you are paying ₹ lakh then ₹
lakh or 105 percent of the total premium paid,
whatever premium you have paid till the date of
death, 105 percent of that or death
benefit multiple times analysed premium
means your death benefit will be multiple
times of analysed premium, so whatever
amount out of this, whatever are the
last three out of the three,
you can see, one, two and three, whichever is the highest among these three, that will be
counted as sum sum,
if you count the premium from this, after
deducting the taxes from the premium, whatever taxes you have paid, you have paid the
rider money, you have paid the extra premium of under rider, there
is some loading, some model  After removing the premiums,
your sum assured is calculated according to the premium that is formed.
So here the
death benefit is calculated in this way.
After that let us talk about how the interim survival
benefit is computed.
See, we have two options, immediate income and guaranteed income.
We have two variants. So,
first of all, what will be the interim survival benefit? The rate of cash bonus will be
multiplied by the analyzed premium
plus guaranteed income. The number of months that have lapsed will be
multiplied by the payout date of the survival benefit. Similarly,
if there is an immediate income with booster, then the
formula for immediate income with booster will also work in the same way. If we
talk about your individual surrender, then if the policy has
completed two years, then in that case
you can surrender it. The guaranteed
surrender value, which is the
factor of guaranteed surrender value, will be the GSP factor
into total premium paid less survival.
Benefit: Whatever amount you have received, paid
till date, you will get that. Now let's talk about
SSV Special Surrender Value. If
two years have been completed, then in that
case it will be calculated in this way.
Its formula will be that the factor SSV will be
multiplied by the total premium
paid. Out of that also the same less survival benefit will be given
which you have received subject
to minimum zero. Plus the terminal bonus
which will be received, if any is attached, then that will be given
along with the contingent terminal bonus which will be
applicable, if reduced, then it will be
declared through the paid policy. Now the
basic details further, whatever balance is left, if the
loan is left, you will get the surrender value at 80%.
After two years, revival can be done within five years
if the policy has lapsed. If we
talk about suicide clause, then
under this policy, if you commit suicide within 12 months, then
no money is received
and if you commit suicide after 12 months,
suicide clause is also covered. Free
look  The grace period is available within this. If you are
taking the policy and are not taking it from a long distance, then there is a
15-day free look period
within which you can close the policy. And
if yes, you have taken the policy from a long distance,
keep it related to the purchase distance mode, then
you get a free look period of 30 days in it.
Further talking about the grace period, there is
15 days in the monthly mode and a
grace period of 30 days is available in the free rest mode. The
cash bonus rate of immediate
income is open in front of you,
you can see it by pausing the screen and
coming here. Our presentation is
complete. So this was the complete
information in which we understood
how you can generate a second source of income, that is,
how you can invest in the gold plan.
How did you like this plan? Please
come and comment in the comment box.
If you have any feedback, whether positive or
negative, related to the plan or
our video, please definitely use the comment box
because your comments  And the feedback is
definitely taken into consideration and
work is definitely done on it. If you
liked the video then like the video and
share it with as many people as possible
so that they can also get information about this plan.
If you have not yet subscribed to the channel then do
not forget to subscribe to the channel by pressing the red button given below.
Finally, thank you very much for watching this video completely
[Music]